<resources>
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">hackatonV1</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="Welcome_text">Welcome to the town hall of Leuven!</string>
    <string name="language_select">Please select your language</string>
    <string name="title_activity_google_maps" translatable="false">Map</string>
    <string name="erasmus" translatable="false">Erasmus</string>
    <string name="vesalius" translatable="false">Vesalius</string>
    <string name="popup_name" translatable="false"></string>
    <string name="statue_name" translatable="false">naam</string>
    <string name="text_mercator">The young Gerard De Kremer (1512-1594) enrolled at the University of Leuven as Gerardus Mercator Rupelmundanus in order to study mathematics. He took on a job in the city as a surveyor after completing his studies. He and his family settled in the Schrijnmakersstraat, near the Mechelsestraat. This scholar was very interested in the universe and his greatest dream was to draw a comprehensive map bookof the earth and the heavens. His life’s work would consume him, but he never finished his atlas. When he died in 1594 in Duisburg (Germany), his descendants were working on his project. It was not completed until 1695 and goes on to become a bestseller.</string>
    <string name="text_margriet">There are many variations on the legend of the Blessed Margaretha of Leuven, some more reliable than others. Margaretha – or Margriet – was born into a poor family 800 years ago. Legend has it that after a robbery in the inn where she worked, she was dragged away to the outskirts of the city by six robbers. She fought them off so bravely that they ultimately killed her, throwing her body in the Dijle River. Instead of floating downstream, her body floated back to Leuven upstream. The Duke himself is said to have witnessed the scene. Margaretha of Leuven was beatified in 1902 and her skull is preserved in Saint Peter’s Church to this very day</string>
    <string name="text_erasmus">Philosopher, writer, critic of the Roman Catholic Church, philologist. It is difficult to put just one label on Desiderius Erasmus (+/-1467-1536), but, regardless of what you call him, he became one of the most important humanistsof the Renaissance. His most famous work is In Praise of Folly, a satirical and critical portrait of mankind. He founded the Collegium Trilingue to promote the knowledge of Greek, Latin, and Hebrew in Leuven. Several prominent scholars of the time, including Mercator, Vesalius, and Dodoens attended lectures here. Erasmus himself translated the New Testament into Latin, using the Greek source text as his basis.</string>
    <string name="text_vesalius">Andreas Van Wesel – also known as Andreas Vesalius(1514-1564) – studied medicine in Leuven and then obtained his doctoratein Padua. At that time, the study of the human body was still based on the centuries-old ideas of the Greek Galenus, which were obsolete, according to Vesalius, who began to dissect bodies out of curiosity and expressed his findings in the beautifully illustrated ‘Humani Corporis Fabrica’. The book incited a revolution in the medical world and Vesalius was appointed as the physician to Emperor Charles V and his son Philip II later on.</string>
    <string name="text_lipsius">Justus Lipsius (1547-1606) came into this world in Overijse and was simply christened Joost Lips. He Latinised his name later, as was customary among humanists. Justus both studied classical literature and law at the University of Leuven in addition to teaching there. However, he did not settle in the tense environment of the Southern Netherlands, transferring to the Calvinistic University in Leiden. The wet climate there erodes his poor health and he moves back to Leuven. As a teacher, he takes care of a group of seven students, mainly the sons of influential friends, who live with him. He died on 24 March 1606 in his house in Leuven.</string>

</resources>